

## STUDENT

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

ruth.raichur@gmail.com 737-217-7954 600 West 26th St, Apt 3402 A, Austin TX 78705 Citizenship: U.S citizen

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## **FUNCTIONAL GENOMICS STREAM - DR. IYER LAB**

University of Texas at Austin (FRI) | January 2019 - Present Peer mentor and Researcher for Functional Genomics Stream

- Research to understand the function and evolution of organisms using next-generation sequencing technologies and the CRISPR-Cas9 system to explore the molecular biology of organisms on a genome-wide scale.
- Working with new FRI students in mastering essential bioscience lab skills and adjusting to the intellectual demands of research.

# **RELEVANT LAB SKILLS**

- Experience in making chemically competent yeast and E.coli cells
- Yeast and E.coli Transformations
- PCR
- Gel Electrophoresis
- DNA and Plasmid extraction
- Gel Extraction
- NanoDrop
- Agar plate preparation

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

## TIDES - FRI AND FIG PAID PEER MENTOR

UT Austin TX | August 2020 - Present

Texas Institute for Discovery Education in Science (TIDES) mentor for an Intro to Research first-year interest group (FIG) for incoming freshmen, assisting in grading and running the course.

#### LIFE AND EARTH SCIENCES MEDIA CONTENT AUTHOR

Macmillan Learning, Austin TX | August 2019 - Present

Assisting the Life and Earth Sciences media content team with authoring and management of online learning systems.

#### LIFE AND EARTH SCIENCES MEDIA CONTENT INTERN

Macmillan Learning, Austin TX | May 2019 - August 2019

#### GRAPHIC DESIGN AND CREATIVE ASSISTANT

Ingenium Global, Dallas TX | September 2018 - May 2019
Design participant guides, slide decks and other forms of visual media for upper-level management training workshops.

## **RESEARCH INTERN**

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India | July 2017 Department of Molecular Biology.

Learned about the genetic techniques employed to decipher the genomic background of neglected diseases, more specifically, the workings of PCR and mass spectroscopy, and a DNA extraction technique. The topic of applying scientific research to benefit the community was discussed.

# **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

# **UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN**

College of Natural Sciences | 2018 - Present

- GPA: 3.8235
- B.S in Biology, Genetics and Genomics (expected May 2022)
- Minor in Business (expected May 2022)
- Credential in Applied Statistical Modeling (expected May 2022)
- Freshman Research Initiative Functional Genomics Stream
- Freshman Research Initiative Peer Mentor
- Texas Chinese Students Association
- University Honors Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Fall 2019, Spring 2020

# MALLYA ADITI INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL, BANGALORE, INDIA

# Class of 2018

- Awarded a Cambridge Advanced International Certificate of Education (AICE) Diploma with Distinction